片名  这个杀手不太冷
“利昂，你到美国多久了？”
“已经很久了”
好…
我们谈谈生意吧
Let's talk business.
这死胖子在插手莫瑞齐奥的生意
This fat bastard is moving in
on Morizio's business.
你知道莫瑞齐奥是个通情达理的人
You know Morizio
is a reasonable guy.
他只是想和他谈谈
He just wants
a little conversation.
但这家伙，根本不理不睬
But this guy.
He don't wanna hear about it.
他可能会听你的话
Maybe he'll listen to you.
他每星期二都会到这儿来
你星期二有空吗？
He comes to town every Tuesday.
Are you free Tuesday?
是的，我星期二有空
Yeah. I'm free Tuesday.
很高兴再次见到您，琼斯先生
Nice to see you again.
Mr. Jones.
记住，做的干净点
Remember. Neatness counts.
你有一个半小时
You got one half hour.
一个小时吧
One hour.
什么事？
What?
我是唐托，楼下的
有个家伙想跟你谈谈
It's Tonto. Downstairs.
There's a guy wants to talk to you.
他看起来咋样？
What's he look like?
很危险
Serious.
- 告诉他我这就过去
- 他正在去你那儿
- Tell him I'm coming up.
- He's coming up.
有人上来了，很危险
Somebody's coming up.
Somebody serious.
米奇，眼睛瞪大点，有客人来了
Mickey. Open your eyes.
We got company.
有客人来了
来啊
Come on.
住手，哥们！
Stop. Man!
是唐托
告诉司机到门口等着，快！
Tell the driver to wait for us
out back. And hurry up.
- 亲爱的，出什么事了？
- 别担心，宝贝
- Sweetie. What's going on?
- Don't worry. Baby.
冷静点，睡一小会儿吧
It's cool. Take a nap.
哦，我的天啊
Oh. My God.
那些傻瓜封锁了所有出口
Those fuckers blocked
both the exits.
到天台看看！
Check the terrace!
- 911紧急救援
- 救命啊
- 911 emergency.
- I need help.
- 有人要杀我
- 别挂啊
- Somebody's trying to kill me.
- Just stay on the line.
稍等一下
I'll just be off a moment.
我给你转一位警官
I'm gonna connect you
with an officer.
我是探员杰斐逊
有什么可以帮忙的吗？
DetectiveJefferson.
May I help you?
我过会儿再打吧
I'll call you back.
别冲动，哥们，我那些箱子里
有半个玻利维亚的毒品
Relax. Man. I got half of Bolivia
sitting in them suitcases.
甚至都没开封，去拿走吧，送你了
Hasn't even been cut yet.
Go ahead. Take it. It's yours.
拨这电话号码
Dial this number.
以后再联络，亲爱的，好吗？
I'll talk to you later.
Sweetie. Okay?
拜拜
Bye.
- 喂？
- 我是莫瑞齐奥，还记得我吗？
- Hello?
- It's Morizio. Remember me?
- 我看见你回来了
- 是啊，我是说，没有
- I see you're back in town.
- Yeah. I mean. No.
今天刚回来
Just for today.
那么可以肯定的说
今天是你在这儿的最后一天了…
So it's safe to say
today's your last day in town...
我们不会再看见你他妈的那张肥脸了吧
and we'll never see
your fat fucking face again.
是的，说的没错
Yeah. Right.
让我跟中间人通话吧
Let me speak
to our mutual friend.
他要跟你通话
He wants to talk to you.
保证他确实明白了，然后放他走吧
Make sure he understands.
And let him go.
你能明白吗？
Do you understand?
- 那就说出来
- 我明白了
- So say it.
- I understand.
很好
Good.
上帝啊
Jesus.
“朋友，跟往常一样，两瓶牛奶？”
Two milk as usual?
为何要把香烟藏起来？
Why did you hide the cigarette?
这大厦的人太多事了
This building's full of rats.
我不想我爸知道，麻烦够多了
I didn't want my old man to find out.
Got enough problems.
出什么事了？
What happened?
我骑自行车摔了
I fell off my bike.
别告发我抽烟的事，好吗？
Don't tell my dad about the cigarette. Okay?
- 为什么你要这样对待我们？
- 我不知道…
- Why are you doing this to us?
- I don't know...
现如今人们记性都不好了
肯定是阳光的问题
People got memory problems these days.
It must be the sun.
- 知道什么时候由阳光产生吗
- 我不知道怎么弄的
- Know when to come out of the sun.
- I don't know how it happened.
我是干啥的？我只是一个保管员
What's my job? I'm just a holder.
我保管你给我的东西，我不看也不碰
I hold the stuff you give to me.
I don't look at it or touch it.
- 我不知道怎样分离
- 听我说
- I don't know how to cut it.
- Try to follow me.
六月份给你的时候百分之百纯度
In June. We gave you the dope.
It tests 100 percent pure.
现在是七月份，我们来拿
纯度变成了百分之九十
Now it's July. We pick up the dope.
And it tests 90 percent pure.
六月和七月之间少了百分之十
Somewhere between June and July.
Ten percent turned to cut!
我不知道，这不关我事
你给我这些东西我就保管
I don't know. It's none of my business.
You give me the stuff. I hold it.
- 我就知道这些
- 我在想法帮你…
- That's all I know.
- I'm trying to help you out here...
但你要真那么肯定…
but if you're gonna be
a hard-ass about it...
我就要去问他了
I gotta disturb him.
当他沉浸在音乐里时
他非常痛恨被打扰
When he's into his music.
He hates being disturbed.
我说的是真话
I'm telling you the truth.
我希望如此，因为他有天赋辨别谎言
I hope so. Because he's got a talent
for sniffin' out a lie.
那很吓人的
It's scary.
几乎就像是第六感
It's almost like a sixth sense.
是你改主意还是我去打扰他？
Are you gonna change your tune
or I gotta bust into his?
我说的是事实
I'm telling you the truth.
好吧
All right.
斯丹
Stan.
对不起，他说他没有做过手脚
I'm sorry.
He said he didn't cut the dope.
他当然没有
Of course he didn't.
帮个忙
Just do me a favor.
明天之前查出来是谁干的
Find out who did by tomorrow.
中午之前
Noon.
马奇，等等
Malky. Wait.
我真没做手脚
I didn't cut your shit.
你自己去查吧！
Find out yourself!
你在外面干什么？回家做作业去
What are you doin' out here?
Get inside and do your homework.
- 我已经做完了
- 回家帮你姐姐…
- I did it already.
- Get inside and help your sister...
打扫这该死的房子！
clean up the goddamn house!
不许再抽烟了！
And stop smoking cigarettes!
一
One!
二，深吸一口气
Two. Take a deep breath in.
深呼一口气
Take a deep breath out.
- 做深呼吸，吸气
- 时间到了，该我了
- Take a deep breath. Inhale.
- Time's up. My turn.
要调台我就痛扁你
Change the channel.
And I'll smash your face.
腿准备，下
Ready for the legs.
And down.
对不起，宝贝
Sorry. Sweetheart.
收紧，放开
Squeeze. Release.
早上好
Good morning.
嗨，宝贝
Hi. Honey.
宝贝，小点声，妈妈头疼
Sweetheart. Turn that down.
Mama's got a headache.
- 她霸占了我的时间
- 她想看该死的卡通片！
- She took my turn.
- She wants to watch goddamn cartoons!
动动屁股不会受伤的
It wouldn't hurt her
to move her ass.
在这儿有大屁股的不是我
I'm not the one
with a fat ass around here.
两下，然后起来
Two and up.
整天除了看卡通片啥也不做的某人…
Can someone who's doing nothing
all day but watching cartoons...
去买点吃的回来好吗？
move a little ass
and go get some food?
- 腿，漂亮
- 我看你再敢那么说
- Legs. Beautiful.
- I dare you to say that again.
- 玛吉，我想我有麻烦了
- 这又不是第一次
- Margie. I think I screwed up.
- It wouldn't be the first time.
你总是能弄出点事来，是不是？
You always come up
with somethin'. Right?
但这次可能有点过分了
I think I went too far this time.
你现在是有点过分，我上班要迟到了
You're goin' too far right now.
I'm gonna be late for work.
今天不上班在家待着咋样？
How about workin'
at home today?
仔细体会下，就是这样，在腹部
Really feel it.
That's it. Stomach in.
- 一…
- 现在该我了！
- One...
- Now it's my turn!
靠！她要打我！
Shit!
She's gonna hit me!
- 爸，她…
- 靠！把那该死的门关上！
- Daddy. She's...
- Shit! Shut the goddamn door!
不要开枪！
Please don't shoot!
他妈的贱货
Fuckin' bitch.
- 威震天！
- 身体要稳
- Megatron!
- Firm up the whole body.
当你使用夸卓拉步法的时候
你的大腿肌肉…
When you use the Quadra-Step.
Your thigh muscles...
- 谁快去接电话啊？
- 我在忙呢！
- Can somebody answer the phone?
- I'm busy!
- 喂？
- 我是玛格丽特・梅考勒斯特…
- Hello?
- This is Marguerite McCallister...
新泽西威尔伍德斯宾塞中学的校长
headmistress at the Spencer School
in Wildwood. NewJersey.
兰度先生或太太在家吗？
Is Mr. Or Mrs. Lando home?
我就是兰度太太
This is she.
兰度太太，您丈夫在斯宾塞
给玛蒂尔达注册的时候…
Mrs. Lando. When your husband
enrolled Mathilda at Spencer...
他告诉我们她有点“问题”
he told us she had "Problems."
我们很乐意教导有问题的小女孩
如您所见，我们很乐意把问题小女孩…
As you know. We pride ourselves
on turning troubled girls...
变成健康，有益的年轻女性
into healthy.
Productive young women.
但如果她们人不在这儿
那我们能做的就很有限了
But if they are not here.
There is very little we can do.
玛蒂尔达已旷课两个星期
Mathilda left school
without permission nearly two weeks ago.
我知道您丈夫已预交了一年学费…
I know your husband paid tuition
in advance for a year...
但如果您查看我们送给您的校规…
but if you will refer to the rules
and regulations manual we sent you...
您会发现，除非有正当理由
可以长期缺席…
you will see that unless there is
a valid excuse for prolonged absence...
否则您的学费将被没收
your tuition will be forfeit.
她已经死了
She's dead.
让那倒霉孩子干点家务活！
Tell that fuckin' kid to do
a little work around here!
清理干净！我受不了他妈的脏东西
Clean up!
I'm tired of this fuckin' mess.
赶紧的！
Hurry up!
$ Why am I feeling
Why am I feeling
$ When things could look black
When things could look black
$ That nothing could possibly go wrong
That nothing
could possibly go wrong
$ This has been a most unusual day
This has been
a most unusual day
$ Love has made me see things
Love has made me see things
$ In a different way
In a different way
生活总是这么难
还是因为你仅仅是个孩子？
Is life always this hard.
Or is it just when you're a kid?
一直这样的
Always like this.
留着吧
Keep it.
我要去杂货店买东西，你要点牛奶吗？
I'm going grocery shopping.
You want some milk?
一夸脱还是两夸脱？是两夸脱吧？
One quart or two?
It's two. Right?
我喜欢暴风雨之前短暂的平静
I like these calm little moments
before the storm.
这让我想起贝多芬
It reminds me of Beethoven.
你能听到吗？
Can you hear it?
就好像你把头贴在草地上
It's like when you put your head
to the grass...
你能听见它的生长
you can hear it growin'.
你能听到那些昆虫
You can hear the insects.
- 你喜欢贝多芬吗？
- 说实在的，不喜欢
- Do you like Beethoven?
- Couldn't really say.
我给你演奏点吧
I'm gonna play you some.
爸爸！
Daddy!
你最好待在这儿
You better stay here.
我们说了是中午
We said noon.
已经过了一分钟了
I've got one minute past.
你不喜欢贝多芬
You don't like Beethoven.
你不知道自己错过了什么
You don't know
what you're missing.
序曲让我浑身舒畅
Overtures like that
get my juices flowing.
那么的有力量
So powerful.
但开场之后，说实在的…
But after his openings.
To be honest...
他就开始有点他妈的乏味了
he does tend to get
a little fucking boring.
这就是为什么我不停下来！
That's why I stopped!
四处搜搜
Toss the apartment.
你喜欢莫扎特，我也喜欢
You're a Mozart fan.
I love him too.
我很喜欢莫扎特
I love Mozart!
你知道他是奥地利人
He was Austrian. You know.
但对于这样的场合
他就有点太轻柔了
But for this kind of work.
He's a little bit light.
所以我要找点带劲儿的家伙
So I tend to go
for the heavier guys.
- 真不错
- 爷们，你他妈的在干吗？
- Cool.
- Dude. What the fuck are you doing?
哥们，闭上你的鸟嘴
Man.
Keep your bombacut mouth shut.
试试勃拉姆斯，他也不错
Check out Brahms.
He's good too.
- 你对音乐知道多少？
- 哥们，别这样！
- What the fuck do you know about music?
- Man. Knock it off!
- 你检查过床垫了吗？
- 没有
- You check the mattress?
- Nope.
哇喔
Wow.
哦，妈的！
Oh! Fuck!
他死了
He's dead.
上帝啊，看看你做了什么
Jesus. Look what you did.
斯丹，你没事吧？
Stan. You all right?
你在干什么？
What are you doin'?
- 他已经死了！
- 但是他毁了我的西服
- He's dead!
- But he ruined my suit.
是的，我知道，但他已经死了
Yeah. I know.
But he's dead.
他现在就是一堆肉，算了吧，冷静点
He's a piece of meat.
Forget about it. Calm down.
我很冷静
I'm calm.
待在这儿，好吗？
Stay there. All right?
班尼！
Benny!
真他妈该死，班尼！
我们是马奇和斯丹！
Jesus fuckin' Christ. Benny!
It's Malky and Stan!
别紧张，好吗？
Take it easy. All right?
来吧
Come on.
班尼！
来吧，我们抽根烟
Come on.
Let's get a cigarette.
班尼，我们要出来了！
Benny. We're comin' out!
班尼，别开枪！
Benny. Don't fire!
到里面去！
Get in there!
真他妈该死，班尼！
Jesus fuckin' Christ. Benny!
你穿了新衣服然后…来个火？
You wear somethin' new and...
Got a light?
放松点
Take it easy.
外面发生什么事了？
What's happening out there?
没事，夫人，禁毒署的
It's all right. Ma'am.
D.E.A. Police.
放过这可怜的一家吧
Leave that poor family alone.
- 一切都正常，冷静点
- 我很冷静，我很冷静
- Everything's all right. Just calm down.
- I am calm. I'm calm.
你们为什么不放过他们？
Why don't you
leave them alone?
他说了，回家去！
He said go back inside.
斯丹，我们还是进去吧
Stan. I think it's better
if we go inside.
班尼，把厨房翻个底朝天！
给我找出来！
Benny. Turn that kitchen upside down!
Find that shit!
威利・布拉德，看看你做了什么！
你杀了一个四岁的小孩儿！
Willy Blood. Iook what you did!
You killed a 4-year-old kid!
你真得必须这样做吗？
Did you really
have to do that?
求求你开门吧
Please open the door.
班尼，应该有三个孩子
Benny.
There are three kids here.
我想斯丹杀的是这个女孩
I think Stan killed this girl.
威利，那个混蛋，杀了那个小男孩
Willy. That asshole.
Shot the little boy.
第三个不见了，把她找出来
The third one's missing.
Find her.
靠，这个小女孩漏网了
Shit. We missed
the little girl. Man.
我去找这该死的大楼管理员
I'm gonna find the fuckin' super
in this goddamn building.
- 你认识我吗？
- 我，钢索，认识你！
- Don't you recognize me?
- Me. Grimlock. Know you!
靠
Shit.
- 呀，我找到了！
- 好！
- Yo! I found it!
- Bingo!
- 他们找到了
- 我知道
- They found it.
- I know.
这就是
There it is.
警察来了，我们最好离开
There's cops outside.
We better go.
警察来了，我们快走吧，你留下
It's the cops outside.
We better go. You stay here.
我怎么说？
What do I say?
告诉他们…
Tell them...
我们在执行公务
we were doing our job.
- 你叫什么名字？
- 玛蒂尔达
- What's your name?
- Mathilda.
- 你父亲的事我很难过
- 就算今天他们不杀他…
- Sorry about your father.
- If somebody didn't do it...
早晚我也会动手的
one day or another.
I would have probably done it myself.
你妈妈，她…
Your mother. She...
她不是我妈妈
She's not my mother.
我姐姐想要减肥，她就那样了
My sister wanted to lose some weight.
Bet she never looked better.
她也不是我亲姐，只是同父异母罢了
She's not even my real sister.
Just a half sister.
那半血统也不怎么好
Not a good half at that.
既然你无法忍受他们
那你为什么要哭？
If you couldn't stand them.
Why are you crying?
我们杀了我弟弟
They killed my brother.
他到底做了什么？他只有四岁
What the hell did he do?
He was four years old.
他从不爱哭
He never used to cry.
他只喜欢坐在我旁边抱着我
He just used to sit
next to me and cuddle.
我对他比那该死的猪更像妈妈
I was more of a mother to him
than that goddamned pig ever was.
不要那样说猪，他们通常比人要友善
Don't talk like that about pigs.
They're usually nicer than people.
但它们臭得要命
But they smell like shit.
不一定
Not true.
事实上，我厨房里现在就有一头…
As a matter of fact.
Right now I have one in my kitchen...
很干净的…
that's very clean...
- 而且闻起来很好
- 你厨房里没有猪
- and smells very nice.
- You don't have a pig in your kitchen.
有的
Yes. I do.
我刚才在那儿，没看见什么该死的猪
I was just in there.
And I didn't see any goddamned pig.
不要动，我去找它
Don't move.
I'll get him.
猪仔，你在哪儿？
Piggy. Where are you?
啊，你在这儿
There you are.
嗨，玛蒂尔达
Hi. Mathilda.
嗨，猪仔
Hi. Piggy.
你今天过得好吗？
How are you today?
不算太好
I've seen better days.
- 你叫什么名字？
- 利昂
- What's your name?
- Leon.
可爱的名字
Cute name.
你有什么人或者地方可投靠吗？
You have anyone to go to.
Any family anyplace else?
我要再来点牛奶
I'm gonna get some more milk.
我靠
Holy shit.
请不要碰
Don't touch that. Please.
你靠什么为生的？
What do you do for a living?
清洁工
Cleaner.
你是一个杀手？
You're a hit man?
酷
Cool.
- 你什么人都杀吗？
- 不杀女人和小孩，那是规矩
- Do you clean anyone?
- No women. No kids. That's the rules.
雇人去收拾那些混蛋要多少钱？
How much would it cost to hire someone
to get those dirtbags...
那些杀了我弟弟的混蛋？
who killed my brother?
- 一人五千
- 哇
- Five grand a head.
- Wow.
我为你工作怎么样…
How about I work for you...
作为交换，你教我怎么杀人？
and in exchange.
You teach me how to clean?
你觉得行不？
What do you think?
我会给你打扫，我会帮你购物
I'll clean your place.
I'll do the shopping.
我会给你洗衣服
I'll even wash your clothes.
- 同意吗？
- 不，我不同意
- Is it a deal?
- No. It's not a deal.
那你让我怎么办？我没有地方可去了
What do you want me to do?
I've got no place to go.
你今天已受够了
You've had a rough day today.
去睡一觉，明天再说
Go to sleep.
And we'll see tomorrow.
你对我真好，利昂…
You've been really great
with me. Leon...
不会总这样的
and it's not always like that.
你知道吗？
You know?
晚安
Good night.
睡得好吗？
You sleep well?
很好
Good.
- 早饭后你就离开吧
- 去哪儿？
- After breakfast you gotta take off.
- Where to?
与我无关
Not my problem.
读一下
Read it.
你不认字
You don't know how to read.
我正在学，但我近来很忙…
I'm learning. But I've had
a lot of work lately...
所以有点退步了
so I'm a little behind.
上面写的什么？
What's it say?
我已经决定今后要做什么了
我要当杀手
I've decided what to do with my life.
I wanna be a cleaner.
你要做杀手，给
You wanna be a cleaner.
Here.
拿去，这是一个送别礼物
去做吧，但别跟着我
Take it. It's a good-bye gift.
Go clean. But not with me.
- 我独来独往，明白吗？
- 邦妮和克莱德从不单独行动
- I work alone. Understand?
- Bonnie and Clyde didn't work alone.
希尔玛和露易丝也从不单独行动
他们是最好的
Thelma and Louise didn't work alone.
They were the best.
玛蒂尔达，你为什么要这样对我？
Mathilda. Why are you
doing this to me?
我不图回报的对你好
I've been nothing
but nice to you.
昨天我救了你一命，就在门口
I saved your life yesterday.
Right outside the door.
对，所以你现在要为之负责了
Right.
Now you're responsible for it.
你肯救我一定是有原因的
If you saved my life.
You must've saved it for a good reason.
如果你现在丢下我不管
这就跟你昨天没开门是一样的…
If you throw me out now.
It's like you never opened your door...
就像你让我在那儿死掉一样
like you let me die
right there in front of it.
但是你开门了，所以…
But you did open it. So...
如果你不帮我，我今晚就会死掉
我能感觉的到
If you don't help me.
I'll die tonight. I can feel it.
我不想今晚就死
I don't wanna die tonight.
玛蒂尔达，你只是一个小女孩
You're just a little girl.
不要这么悲观，但我觉得你做不了
Don't take it badly.
But I don't think you could do it.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
怎么样？
How's that?
不许再这么做，否则我打爆你脑袋
Don't you ever do that again
or I'll break your head.
明白吗？
You got that?
我不会那样做的，那不专业
I don't work like that.
It's not professional.
那是规矩
There is rules.
不要总说“好的”！
And stop saying "okay"
all the time!
好的
Good.
你打算在这酒店里用那个吗？
You expect to use that
in this hotel?
先生，我必须用它…
Mister. I have to use it...
因为我下个月要在朱利亚德试演…
because I have an audition
atJuilliard next month...
所以我必须练习
and I have to practice.
好吧，但不能超过十点
Okay. But not after 10:00.
- 我保证
- 好吧
- I promise.
- All right.
我会把你们安排在最里头的房间…
I'll put you
at the end of the hall...
那样你们不会打扰别人
so that you
dongt disturb anyone.
请填表
Fill those out. Please.
爸爸，能让我填吗？
我一向喜欢填酒店表格的
Daddy. Can I please fill them out?
I like to check in to hotels.
谢谢，爸，我马上拿回来
Thanks. Pop.
I'll bring these back in a minute.
四楼！
Fourth floor!
谢谢，先生！
Thanks. Mister!
你很走运，有这么一个
生气勃勃的小女孩
You're lucky to have a little girl
that's interested in things.
我有个小孩，十七岁了
整日啥也不干
I have a kid. 17.
Does nothing all day long.
我把行李拿上楼的时候
先把盆栽放在这儿好吗？
Can I leave my plant here
while I take my stuff upstairs?
当然可以
Of course.
我填的是班里一个
让我讨厌的同学的名字
I'm putting in a name of a girl
in my class who makes me sick.
如果出事了，就让她去处理
If things get hot.
She'll take the heat.
给，填好了
There. Finished.
- 你多大啦？
- 十八
- How old are you?
- Eighteen.
- 十八？
- 想看我的出生证明吗？
- Eighteen?
- Want to see my license?
不用，你只是看上去很年轻
No. You just look a little young.
谢谢
Thanks.
利昂，我希望你让我
成为跟你一样的人
Leon. I want you to teach me
how to be like you.
我想要像你一样强壮和聪明
I want to be strong and smart
like you.
我知道我还不够强壮…
I know I'm not
strong enough yet...
但我可以从基本理论学起
but I could learn the basics.
The theory.
你觉得怎样？仅仅是理论
What do you think?
Just the theory.
我需要这样，利昂
I need this. Leon.
我需要时间来整理思路
I need time to get my head together.
是的，我需要…
Yeah. And I need...
来一杯
a drink.
别动，我去
Dongt move.
I'll go get one.
当你告诉我你要这种婴儿玩具…
When you told me
to get this baby out for you...
我还以为我听力有问题
I thought my hearing was going.
我对自己说，“利昂是一个专家
除了菜鸟没人用那个”
I says to myself. " Leongs a pro.
Nobody uses that except beginners."
我想保持状态
I like to stay in shape.
好，总保持领先
Sure.
Always stay on top of it.
这就像我，我必须掌握所有情况
It's like me. I gotta know
where everything is all the time.
我稳稳的坐在这儿而不是东躲西藏
I never leave this place.
Except to go from here to there.
改变不怎么好，利昂，你知道吗？
Change aingt good. Leon.
You know?
检查一下吧
Check it.
- 看看是否你要的
- 我相信你
- Make sure it's the right thing.
- I trust you.
相信别人容易出事，记住了
One thing's got nothing to do
with the other. Remember that.
我会的
I will.
步枪是你学习使用的第一件武器…
The rifle is the first weapon
you learn how to use...
因为它让你跟目标保持距离
because it lets you
keep your distance from the client.
你越专业…
The closer you get
to being a pro...
你就离目标越近
the closer you can get
to the client.
例如刀之类的武器，是你最后要学的
The knife. For example.
Is the last thing you learn.
就位
Position.
不到最后一刻不要打开，它会反光的
Never take it off until the last minute.
It reflects light.
他们会在一英里外就看到你
They can see you coming
from a mile away.
要穿深色衣服
And always dress down.
不能比地面显眼，明白吗？
Never brighter
than the floor. Okay?
我们现在开始练习吧
这是学习的最佳方法
Let's practice now.
It's the best way to learn.
我应该打哪儿？
Who should I hit?
随便
Whoever.
等下就来，等我几分钟，谢谢
I'll be with you in a second.
Give me a few minutes. Thank you.
你们这些家伙给我消失
我不想看见你们
You guys get lost.
I dongt want to see you.
- 人人就位了吗？
- 这看起来自然多了
- Is everyone in position?
- This has to look natural.
- 不杀女人，不杀小孩，对吧？
- 对
- No women. No kids. Right?
- Right.
那个穿黄橙相间的慢跑的？
Jogger in the yellow and orange?
保持冷静
Keep calm.
视线不要离开目标
Dongt take your eyes off him.
轻呼吸
Breathe easy.
观察他的动作
Watch his movement.
假装自己正在和他一起跑
Pretend you're running with him.
试着感觉他下一个动作
Try to feel his next movement.
深呼吸，保持住
Take a deep breath.
Hold it.
动手
Now.
哦，我的天啊！
Oh. My God!
- 我没事，我很好
- 趴下！哪里来的？
- I'm all right. I'm fine.
- Get down! Where'd that come from?
一枪中的，不错吧？
One shot. Not bad. Huh?
- 到底谁开的枪？
- 我喘不过来气了，闪一边去
- Who the hell fired?
- I just cangt breathe! Get off me.
我们现在能试试实弹吗？
Can we try
with real bullets now?
今天不行，收工
Not today.
Let's pack up.
就像这样
Like that.
- 不，谢了
- 没的商量
- No. Thanks.
- No discussion.
“看起来…
"It seemed...
就像苏格拉底…”
to Socrates..."
让我来吧
I'll do it.
利昂，我们不停的工作
Leon. All we do is work.
我们需要休息，我们做游戏吧
We need a break.
Let's play a game.
- 什么样的游戏？
- 我知道一个很棒的游戏
- What kind of game?
- I have this great game.
它有助思考和记忆，正是你需要的
It makes you think and helps your
memory. It's exactly what you need.
$ Like a virgin
Like a virgin
$ Touched for the very first time
Touched for the very first time
- 好，这是谁？
- 我不知道
- Who is it?
- I dongt know.
$ Happy birthday to you
Happy birthday to you
$ Happy birthday, Mr.President
Happy birthday. Mr. President
我不知道
I dongt know.
小胡子
Moustache.
$ I'm singing in the rain
I'm singing in the rain
$ Just singing in the rain
Just singing in the rain
- $ What a beaut...
- 吉恩・凯利？
- What a beaut...
- Gene Kelly?
好
Good.
该你了
Your turn now.
好了，旅行者
Okay. Pilgrim.
克林特・伊斯特伍德
Clint Eastwood?
- 我不知道，我弃权
- 约翰・韦恩
- I dongt know. I give up.
- John Wayne.
我刚要说的，我发誓，这让人吃惊
I was just about to say that.
I swear. It's amazing.
利昂，真的很棒
Leon. Really brilliant.
不可思议
Amazing.
- 你很喜欢那盆栽，是不是？
- 它是我最好的朋友
- You love your plant. Dongt you?
- It's my best friend.
总是快乐，从不提问
Always happy.
No questions.
它就像我一样，你看
It's like me. You see.
没有根
No roots.
如果你真爱它，你应该把它
种到公园里，那它就会有根了
If you really love it. You should
plant it in a park so it can have roots.
你应该来浇灌我
如果你想让我长大的话
You should be watering me
if you want me to grow.
你说的对
You're right.
不要！
Wait!
它们就像要从餐具里跳出来
它们好像活了一样
They gotta be jumping out of the plate.
They gotta be alive.
好久不见了，利昂
It's been a long time. Leon.
我常想你
I missed you.
- 而且你错过了很多好活儿
- 我在培训
- And you missed some nice jobs too.
- Been training.
培训是好事，但不要做过头了
Training's good.
But dongt overdo it.
培训跟干活的收益不能相提并论，利昂
Training dongt pay
as good as working. Leon.
托尼…
Tony...
我挣的所有的钱，放在你那儿的…
all the money I make.
That you keep for me...
你需要钱吗？
You need some money?
随便问问
Just curious.
我干活干了很久了…
I've been working
a long time...
却从没用钱做过什么事
and I havengt done anything
with my money.
我想可能有一天要用
I thought maybe
someday I could use it.
你有女人了
You met a woman.
利昂，你要小心女人
You gotta be careful
with women.
还记得你来这个国家的时候吗？
Remember when you arrived
in this country?
当我把你领上道时，你乳臭未干…
When I took you in. You were still wet
behind the fucking ears...
就是因为一个女人搞的一团糟
and. Already. You were in deep shit
because of a woman.
- 不要忘了，利昂
- 我希望我能忘了
- Dongt forget that. Leon.
- I wish I could sometimes.
你知道，关于我的钱…
You know. About my money...
或许我可以送…
Maybe I could give...
一点儿…
a little...
给某人
to someone.
你知道，帮人救急
You know. To help out.
这是你的钱，我只是帮你保管
就像银行一样
It's your money. I'm just
holding it for you. Like a bank.
甚至比银行更好
因为银行经常会倒闭的
Except better than a bank
because banks always get knocked off.
老托尼这儿不会倒闭
No one knocks off old Tony.
而且，去银行…
Besides. With a bank...
要填很多表格
there's always tons of forms
and all that shit.
但在老托尼这儿，什么也不用看
什么也不用填，都在脑子里
But old Tony. Nothing to read.
Nothing to write. It's all in his head.
我现在识字了
I know how to read now.
不错，利昂
That's good. Leon.
你的钱在这儿
Your money's here.
无论何时你要取，你就来找我
Whenever you want it.
You just ask me.
- 这是一千块，拿着吧
- 没事，我用不着
- Here's a grand. Come on.
- It's okay. I dongt need it.
- 拿走吧，找点乐子，去吧
- 谢谢
- Take it. Have some fun. Go ahead.
- Thank you.
好了，现在我们谈谈生意吧
All right.
Now let's talk business.
不要走，我去拿资料
Dongt move.
I'll go get the file.
麦诺劳，给我朋友利昂来杯牛奶
Manolo. A glass of milk
for my friend Leon here.
听着，玛蒂尔达，你要小心点
Listen. Mathilda.
You better be careful.
你不能随便跟街上的人讲话
You cangt just speak
to any guy off the street.
利昂，放心吧，这有他妈的什么啊？
Leon. Get a grip.
What's the big fucking deal?
我只是在等待的时候找根烟抽
I was just smoking a butt
while I was waiting.
我不许你说粗话
I want you to stop cursing.
你不能总是这样跟人讲话的
You cangt talk to people
like that all the time.
我希望你讲话文明点
I want you to make an effort
to talk nice.
而且我不许你再抽烟，那会要你命的
And I want you to stop smoking.
It will kill you.
离他远一点，他看起来好像有毛病
Stay away from him.
He looks like a weirdo.
我过五分钟就出来
待在我能看见你的地方
I'll be out in five minutes.
Stand where I can see you.
利昂，我想我已经爱上你了
Leon. I think I'm kinda
falling in love with you.
这是我的初恋，你知道吗
It's the first time for me.
You know.
你怎么知道那就是爱情
如果你以前从没有爱过的话
How do you know it's love
if you've never been in love before?
因为我能感觉的到
'Cause I feel it.
哪儿？
Where?
在我的胃里面
In my stomach.
很温暖
It's all warm.
我以前总感觉胃里打结，现在消失了
I always had a knot there.
And now it's gone.
玛蒂尔达，我很高兴你胃病好了
Mathilda. I'm glad you
dongt have a stomachache anymore.
我不觉得那有什么意义
I dongt think
it means anything.
我干活要迟到了，我干活不喜欢迟到
I'm late for work.
I hate being late for work.
嘿，练的怎么样了？
How's the practicing going?
- 今天怎么样，小姐？
- 有点不想练了
- How are we today. Miss?
- A little sick of practicing.
我能理解
I understand.
但你做的不错
But you're doing all right.
我没听到有人抱怨
I havengt received
any complaints.
我用布把发声部包了起来以降低噪音
I put a cloth over the strings
to lessen the noise.
真聪明
That's very smart.
- 不是人人都爱音乐的
- 我知道
- Not everyone loves music.
- I know.
你父亲究竟是干那一行的？
What does your father do?
- 他是一个作曲家
- 太棒了
- He's a composer.
- That's wonderful.
可惜他不真的是我父亲
Except he's not really my father.
他是我的爱人
He's my lover.
我要出去散散步
Think I'll go for a walk.
- 你周六晚上有事吗？
- 一起吃晚饭好吗？
- What are you doing Saturday night?
- What about dinner?
- 你要去哪儿？
- 到6J看朋友
- Where you going?
- Visiting friends at 6J.
去吧，周六怎么样？
Go ahead.
What about Saturday?
- 八点行吗？
- 我不知道
- About 8:00?
- I dongt know.
你有事？
You got plans?
就在这儿见？
Meet you here?
我们知道你很忙，我们尽快完事
We know you're a busy man.
We'll make this short.
如果你能详细告诉我们发生了什么
If you'll just take us step-by-step
through exactly what happened.
那家伙在这儿，他要去拿枪
The guy was here.
He went for his gun.
砰，我们向他开枪…
Bang. We shot him.
- 那些孩子在哪儿？
- 我不知道！
- Where exactly were the kids?
- I dongt know!
他们应该在学校，你不认为吗？
They should have been at school.
Dongt you think?
你的陈述说你是第一个进屋的
Your statement said
you were the first man in.
- 你没看到孩子吗？
- 门被打破了
- Didngt you see any kids?
- The door was broken.
发生了什么？你按程序来的吗？
What happened?
Did you follow the procedure?
在这儿我损失了一个好手
你他妈的想让我怎么办？
I lost a good man here.
What the fuck do you want with me?
合作
Cooperation.
我没有时间和你们胡扯
I havengt got time
for this Mickey Mouse bullshit!
你想要合作？来我办公室，4602房间
You want cooperation?
Come up in my office. Room 4602.
小孩应该在学校
Kids should be at school.
拜托，那是我的球！
Come on. That's my ball!
还给我，你要去哪儿？
Give that back.
Where you going?
该死！你要去哪儿，哥们？
那是我的球！
Damn! Where you going. Man?
That's my ball!
跟着那辆蓝色轿车
Follow the blue car.
你是要我鸣着警笛闯红灯吗？
You want me to blast the music
and go through the lights?
不是，慢慢开吧
No. Drive slowly.
拿着这一百块，闭上他妈的嘴
Take the hundred bucks.
And shut the fuck up.
I do not want to fight you.
but you leave me no choice.
我不想跟你打，但你让我别无选择
小子，你刚让我有了一个好主意！
Boy.you just gave me
a great idea!
- 我的意思是一个大个的！
- 欢迎回到E频道，每日新闻…
- I mean a big one!
- Welcome back to E! News Daily...
最新30分钟娱乐资讯
our 30-minute look at the latest
in entertainment news.
我是碧昂卡・菲尔罗
I'm Bianca Ferrar.
这是给你的，一个礼物
It's for you.
A present.
需要我来打开吗？我来打开吧
Do you want me to open it?
I'll open it.
你喜欢吗？不错吧？
How do you like it?
Nice. eh?
麦克拉芬先生？
Mr. McGuffin?
我可以跟你谈谈吗？
Can I have a word with you?
给，合同款，两万，对吧？
Here. It's for a contract.
Twenty grand. right?
他叫诺曼・斯丹斯菲尔德
住4602房间
His name is Norman Stansfield.
and he's in room 4602...
在联邦广场26号禁毒署大厦
in the D.E.A. building.
26 Federal Plaza.
- 我不干
- 为什么？
- I'm not taking it.
- Why not?
- 太难了
- 好吧
- It's too heavy.
- Well.
那天你把装备租给我好吗？
Will you rent me your gear
for the day?
我的装备概不外借
I never lend out my gear.
但是…
But...
你有自己的枪，用它吧
you still have your gun.
Use it.
帮个忙，别往窗外开枪了
Just do me a favor.
Dongt shoot out the window.
你为什么对我这么吝啬？
Why are you so mean to me?
粗暴的杀人你啥话不说…
Wildly killing people
you dongt give a shit about...
却对杀了我全家的那些混蛋置之不理？
but you wongt get the bastards
that killed my whole family?
报仇并不是好事，一旦你做过之后
相信我
Revenge is not good
once you're done. Believe.
- 最好忘了吧
- 忘了？
- It's better to forget.
- Forget?
在我看过我弟弟的尸体
在地板上的轮廓线之后…
After I've seen the outline
of my brother's body on the floor...
你期望我能忘掉？
you expect me to forget?
我要杀了那些婊子养的
I want to kill
those sons of bitches.
打爆他们他妈的头
Blow their fucking heads off.
你杀了人之后一切都不一样了
Nothing's the same
after you've killed someone.
你的人生会永久的改变
Your life is changed forever.
你余生连睡觉都得睁一只眼闭一只眼
You have to sleep with one eye open
for the rest of your life.
我才不关心睡着了以后的事，利昂
I dongt give a shit
about sleeping. Leon.
我需要爱…
I want love...
或是死亡
or death.
就这样！
That's it.
我想要死亡
I want death.
放过我吧，玛蒂尔达
我已经厌倦了你的游戏
Get off my case. Mathilda.
I'm tired of your games.
这个游戏真的很棒，利昂
There's this really great game. Leon.
对人有益，让他们开始思考
Makes people nicer.
Starts them thinking.
你喜欢的那种游戏
The kind of game you love.
如果我赢了…
If I win...
你要跟我…一生一世
you keep me with you...
for life.
如果你输了呢？
And if you lose?
你自己去买东西吧，就像以前一样
Go shopping alone. like before.
你会输的，玛蒂尔达
You're gonna lose. Mathilda.
子弹已经上膛了，我听出来了
There's a round in the chamber.
I heard it.
那又如何？
So what?
如果我被子弹击中头部终结一生
你会怎样？
What's it to you if I end up
with a bullet in the head?
没什么
Nothing.
我希望你没有撒谎，利昂
I hope you're not lying. Leon.
我真希望你内心深处没有爱情
I really hope that deep down inside
there's no love in you.
因为如果有…
Because if there is...
哪怕那么一丁点儿对我的爱…
just a little bit of love in there
for me...
我想等会儿你就会为沉默而后悔
I think that in a few minutes
you'll regret you never said anything.
我爱你，利昂
I love you. Leon.
我赢了
I win.
我中了一枪
I took a hit.
我需要个助手
I need a hand now.
我知道她还小，但她学的很快
I know she's young.
but she learns fast.
孩子需要目标去成长，对吧？
Kids need to be shaped
into something. right?
我知道，是我教给你的
但不是有年龄限制吗？
I know. I taught you that.
But aingt there an age limit?
她十八岁了
She's 1 8.
真的？
Really?
有什么喝的吗，托尼？
How about something to drink. Tony?
当然了，麦诺劳，给利昂一杯牛奶
Sure. Manolo. glass of milk
for Leon.
纹身挺靓
Nice tattoo.
麦诺劳，拿两杯来
Manolo. make that two.
- 那是干什么？
- 感冒了可治不起啊
- What's that for?
- Cangt afford to catch cold.
首先你要找出防盗链在哪儿
First you find out
where the chain is.
你看不见，但你能感觉到，这儿
You cangt see it.
but you can feel it. Here.
- 我要按铃，你讲话
- 我说什么？
- I'll ring. you start talking.
- What do I say?
随你便
Whatever you want.
- 谁啊？
- 嗨
- Yes?
- Hi.
我是苏珊
It's Susan.
对不起，你走错门了，小姑娘
I'm sorry. You must have
the wrong door. little girl.
我不认识什么苏珊
I dongt know any Susan.
往后站点儿，我什么也看不见
Move back a little.
I cangt see anything.
灯不亮了
The light's out.
外面很黑
It's all dark out here.
- 先生，我很害怕
- 好吧
- Mister. I'm scared.
- Okay.
你他妈的干什么？
What the fuck are you doing?
张开
Open up.
只要松嘴我就开枪
If it leaves your mouth.
I'll pull the trigger. capisce?
没事，松开吧
Here's okay.
Let it go.
我说了，“松开吧”
I said. '' Let it go.''
过去，去那边
Move. Move over.
放松，放松
Easy. Easy.
放松，小心点，你先让我…
Easy. Careful.
You want me--
去吧，该你了
Go ahead. Your turn.
求求你，不要打我
Help me.
Please dongt beat me.
先生？
Sir?
先生，这不是我的毒品
Sir. it's not my dope.
先生，看我
Sir. look I--
请靠左一点
A little left. please.
之前…请…
Before-- Ple--
现在，补射一枪
Now. the security shot.
不，第二枪要打在胸部上面一点
No. the second goes
higher on the chest.
瞄准心脏和肺部
Aim for the heart and lungs.
这儿，就这儿，你明白吗？
There. Right there.
You see?
第一枪让他丧失行动能力
The first shot takes him
out of order.
- 第二枪要他的命
- 你们他妈的在干什么？
- The second finishes him off.
- What are you fucking doing?
别打脸
Never in the face.
如果他们认不出目标来
你就挣不到钱
If they cangt recognize the client.
you dongt get paid.
因为你有可能随便杀个人交差
You could take out anybody
and said you did the job.
- 明白了吗？
- 明白了，不要打脸
- Got it?
- Got it. Never in the face.
- 现在你可以去收拾装备了
- 你们他妈的在干什么？
- Now you can put the tools away.
- What are you fucking doing?
接下来他妈的又干什么？嘿，先生！
What the fuck is going on?
Hey. mister!
你他妈的…
What are you fuckin--
你看见了没，当你消声器用多了之后…
You see. when you use
the silencer a lot...
你就必须放块布在这儿…
you have to put
a piece of cloth here...
因为它非常热，在里面可能烧起来
because it gets very hot
and could burn it inside.
黑湿布最好
A damp. black cloth is the best.
你在干什么？
What you doing?
我们说了不杀妇孺
We said no women. no kids.
你觉得这些会杀了谁？
吸毒的和猴子吗？
Who do you think this is gonna kill.
junkies and monkeys?
现在干净了
Now it's clean.
我们走吧
Let's get out of here.
我觉得我们不应该喝酒
I thought we dongt have
the right to drink.
我知道，但为了你的第一次
我们可以例外一次
I know. but we're making
an exception for your first time.
好吧，如果我们为了一个
做的漂亮的活儿而例外的话…
Well. if we're making exceptions
for a job well-done...
来个吻怎么样，就像电影里那样？
how about a kiss.
like in the movies?
好
Yes.
你要干什么？
What you doing?
- 我要吻你
- 我要你停下，求你了
- I'm going to kiss you.
- I want you to stop. please.
来吧，仅仅是一个吻
Come on.Just a kiss.
停下，别人在看我们呢
Stop. Everyone is watching us.
坐下
Go sit down.
请慢用
Enjoy.
- 你不相信我，是不是？
- 何以见得？
- You dongt believe me. do you?
- How's that?
- 我说我爱上你时
- 玛蒂尔达，换个话题吧
- When I say I'm in love with you.
- Mathilda. please drop it.
- 换个题目，好不好？
- 好，对不起
-Just change the subject. okay?
- Okay. Sorry.
那么，你第一次失恋是多大？
So. how old were you
when you made your first hit?
十九
Nineteen.
打击很大吧
Beat you.
- 你在干什么？
- 感冒了可治不起啊
- What you doing?
- Cangt afford to catch a cold.
- 没有门铃
- 那就敲门
- There's no doorbell.
- So knock on the door.
- 谁啊？
- 嗨
- Yes?
- Hi.
我找鲁本先生的房间…
I'm looking
for Mr. Reubengs apartment...
但是大堂很黑，我迷路了
but it's all dark out here
in the hall. and I'm lost.
等等
Just a second.
还要吗？来啊，让我看看你他妈的脸
You want more? Come on.
Show your fucking face.
你以为你能很容易的搞定我？
You think you're going to
get me that easily?
当遇到这样又臭又硬的
你就要知道这事不容易了
When it's tough like this.
you know it's gonna be ugly.
最好速战速决，否则我们
就要一直听他说那些废话
Better make it quick or else
we'll be all day listening to his crap.
傻瓜！来啊
让我看看你他妈的脸，废柴！
Asshole! Come on. show me
your fucking face. faggot!
- 来啊，耍把戏的
- 嘿
- Come on. gum trick.
- Hey.
你知道什么是指环把戏吗？
What about the ring trick?
You know that one?
指环把戏？来啊，混球，我在等着呢
Ring trick? Come on. asshole.
I'm waiting.
耍给我看看，杂种
Show it to me. motherfucker.
这就是指环把戏
That's the ring trick.
马里奥，回理发店去，迟点再剪吧
Mario. go back to the barbershop.
We'll finish later.
利昂，怎样了？一切妥当了吗？
Leon. what's up?
All done already?
比一般人强啊，是吧？
Nicer than people. eh?
我早就说过的
I told you that.
- 你有麻烦了吗？
- 没有
You got a problem?
找张椅子，坐吧
Get the chair. Sit down.
我在思考
I was thinking.
如果某天我出事了
If something happens
to me someday--
嘿，利昂，你什么事都不会有的
Hey. Leon.
nothing's gonna happen to you.
你是刀枪不入的，你可以与子弹共舞
You're indestructible. Bullets
slide off you. You play with 'em.
托尼，我在为我的钱思考
Tony. I thought about my money.
你还记得那天来这儿的
那个小女孩儿吗？
You remember the girl
who came here the other day?
她的名字是玛蒂尔达
Her name is Mathilda.
如果我出事了…
If anything happens to me...
我希望你…
I'd like you...
把我的钱…
to give her...
给她
my money.
没问题，利昂
You can count on me. Leon.
谢谢你，托尼
Thank you. Tony.
我很快就回来
I wongt be long.
- 我做错了什么吗？
- 没有
- Did I do something wrong?
- No.
这次的活儿很棘手
This one is too big.
是啊，我只能干点儿小活儿，是不是？
Yeah. and I only get the leftovers.
is that it?
玛蒂尔达，自从遇到你以…
Mathilda. since I met you...
一切都不同了
everything's been different.
所以我只是想单独呆一阵
So I just need some time alone.
你需要时间来长大一点
You need some time
to grow up a little.
我已经长大了，利昂
I finished growing up. Leon.
我正在变老
I just get older.
在我看来正好相反，我太老了
For me it's the opposite.
I'm old enough.
我需要时间成长
I need time to grow up.
靠
Shit.
快点！抢位！
Come on! Hustle!
- 投的好
- 来啊
- Good shot.
- Come on.
你是新来的吧？五楼的对吧？
You're new. arengt you?
Fifth floor. right?
- 你不能坐这儿
- 真的？为什么？
- You cangt sit here like that.
- Really. why not?
没有什么是免费的，就像停车表
Nothing's free.
Like a parking meter.
当你停下来的时候
你就得付钱，这是规矩
When you stop. you pay.
It's the law.
- 那是在电视上
- 你说什么？
- Only on T.V.
- What'd you say?
- 算了，你要多少钱？
- 十块…
- Forget it. How much is your meter?
- Ten dollars...
每个月
a month.
能找钱吗？
Got change?
没关系，我先付十个月的
Dongt worry about it.
We'll do ten for twelve.
我现在付的是到年底的
I'll pay now for
the rest of the year.
好，算一年
Okay. a year.
付了租金你们这些家伙就
不能来烦我了吧？
Does paying rent here mean
I have to put up with you guys?
那就去别的地方玩吧
So go play somewhere else.
我要想事情
I need to think.
站直了，你还想不想干了？
Stand up.
Dongt you like your job?
吃的
Food.
- 你要去哪儿？
- 专程送达4602房间
- Where you going?
- Special delivery. room 4602.
在这儿签名
Sign here.
过来啊
Come here.
- 周末玩得开心点，姑娘们
- 多谢
- Have a nice weekend. girls.
- Thanks.
我要去趟厕所
I'm gonna go
to the restroom.
专程送达的？
Special delivery?
让我猜猜
Let me guess.
中餐？
Chinese?
要不是泰国菜？
Thai. maybe?
我知道那是什么了
I've got it.
意大利菜
Italian food.
你叫什么名字，小乖乖？
What's your name. angel?
玛蒂尔达
你把那袋子放到地上去
I want you to put the sack
on the floor.
好…
Good.
现在我要你告诉我
你对意大利菜知道多少
Now I want you to tell me everything
you know about Italian food.
还有那做菜的大厨是谁？
Dongt forget the name of the chef
who fixed it for me.
没人派我来，我为自己做事
Nobody sent me.
I do business for myself.
那就代表…
So this is something...
是私人恩怨，是不是？
personal. is it?
我到底做了…
What filthy piece of shit...
什么坏事了？
did I do now?
你杀了我弟弟
You killed my brother.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
你想去看他吗？
And you wanna join him?
事情总是如此
It's always the same thing.
当你开始真正害怕死亡的时候…
It's when you start to become
really afraid of death...
你就会开始重视生命
that you learn
to appreciate life.
你喜欢生命吗，宝贝儿？
Do you like life.
sweetheart?
那真不错
That's good.
因为我会没有压力…
Because I take no pleasure...
去杀一个…
in taking a life...
不关心生死的人
if it's from a person
who doesngt care about it.
斯丹，我在到处找你
Stan. I've been looking
all over for you.
- 我找过楼上…
- 干什么？我在忙
- I checked upstairs--
- What? I'm busy.
是马奇，哥们，他死了
It's Malky. man.
He's dead.
马奇为我们去跟中国人做买卖
Malky was making a buy for us
from the Chinaman.
但这事不是中国人干的
But they got nothing
to do with it.
他们说这家伙是外地的，他是职业的
They told me this guy came
from the outside. He was a pro.
他出手很快，他妈的无处不在
He was fast.
He fuckingcame out of nowhere.
很猛，不到两秒就干掉了中国人
Boom. shoots the Chinaman dead
in two seconds.
放松，哥们，我是警察
Easy. man.
I'm a cop.
然后转了个身，对马奇说…
Then turns around.
says something to Malky like--
不能杀女人和小孩儿
No women. no kids.
我觉得是私人恩怨
I think
it was something personal.
在今天死亡就不算个事
Death is whimsical today.
布拉德，能听到我说话吗？
Blood. do you hear me?
能，我听着呢，斯丹，冷静点，哥们
Yeah. I hear you. Stan.
Just chill out. man.
你把她带到我办公室好吗？
Would you take her
up to my office?
好的
All right.
真他妈的！
Jesus fucking Christ.
“利昂，我的爱人
''Leon. my love.
我已经找到了那些杀害我弟弟的家伙
I know where to find the guys
who killed my brother.
他们的头儿叫诺曼・斯丹斯菲尔德
在禁毒署大厦4602房间
Their boss is Norman Stansfiield.
He's in the D.E.A. building. room 4602.
我要亲手干掉他们
I'm gonna do them myself.
如果出事的话
我在桌上给你留了两万块
If something goes wrong.
I left you 20 grand on the table.
这是一个合同，一个五千，好吗？
It's for a contract.
Five grand a head. right?
我知道做了这些之后我会感觉好点儿的
I know I'll feel better
after I do this.
我爱你，玛蒂尔达”
I love you. ''
等一下，我马上就回来
Wait. I wongt be long.
我不能在这儿停车，这是联邦大厦！
I cangt park in front like this.
It's a federal building!
他必须按我说的办
He's gonna do the same exact thing
that I said.
一把九毫米手枪
A nine ''millie.''
子弹
Bullets.
另一把九毫米手枪
Another nine ''millie.''
你打算用这些枪来干什么？
What'd you plan to do
with all these guns?
她可能想杀掉整座大厦的人
Maybe she was planning on
taking out the whole building.
我靠！
Holy shit!
这是什么？午餐啊
What's this? Lunch.
小心点，布拉德，可能有毒
Careful. Blood.
might be poisoned.
没有凤尾鱼啊
There's no anchovies on this.
这就是你说的“我马上回来”？
我等了十分钟了
Is that what you call ''I wongt be long''?
I been here for ten minutes.
我尽最大努力了
I did my best.
你喜欢吗？
Do you like it?
是的
Yes.
那就说出来
So say it.
我喜欢
I like it.
不渴吗？
Not thirsty?
你要知道，一个女孩的第一次很重要
You know. a girl's first time
is very important.
那决定了她一生的性福
It determines the rest
of her life sexually.
我在我姐姐的杂志上读过一篇
I read that once in one
of my sister's magazines.
我的朋友们告诉我
她们痛恨第一次的经历
My girlfriends told me
they hated their first experience.
那是因为她们根本就不爱那些家伙
That's because
they didngt love the guys.
她们做只是因为炫耀
They just did it to show off.
接下来，她们开始喜欢做，喜欢抽烟
Afterwards. they started liking it.
like cigarettes.
我的第一次会高兴吗？
Will I like it the first time?
玛蒂尔达，不行
Mathilda. no.
为什么？
Why not?
就是不行
I just cangt.
- 你另有所爱？
- 不是
- You love someone else?
- No.
我的意思是…
I mean--
很久之前有个人
There was someone a long time ago.
在我来美国之前
Before I came to the States.
她父亲不想让她见我
Her father didngt want her
to see me.
她出身名门
She was from
a very respectable family.
而我…
Mine was...
你知道…
you know...
没什么名望
not so respectable.
她父亲百般阻挠她来见我
Her dad went nuts every time
she'd take off to see me.
但她仍不死心，对吧？
She still snuck off
to see you. right?
对
Right.
看见了没，没什么能阻止爱情，利昂
See. nothing can stop love. Leon.
他父亲杀了她
He killed her.
一枪射在头上
One shot through the head.
他们把他投进大牢，两天后获释
They kept him in jail for two days.
and they let him go free.
他们说那是一个意外
They said it was an accident.
所以
So...
一天晚上，我…
one night I...
等到了他
waited for him.
500英尺开外我带着瞄准镜
Five hundred feet with a lens.
于是他也有了一个意外
He also had an accident.
当天晚上我乘船来到了这儿…
The same night I took a boat
and came here...
遇到了我父亲，他在给托尼干活儿
to meet up with my father
who was working for Tony.
那时我十九岁
I was 1 9.
从此我再没离开这座城市，而且…
Since then I've never left
the city. and...
我再没有找女朋友
I've never had another girlfriend.
你明白吗，玛蒂尔达…
You see. Mathilda...
我不会是一个好恋人的
I wouldngt be a good lover.
好吧
Okay.
你能帮我一个忙吗？
Would you do me one favor?
什么？
What?
看到你在椅子上睡觉很不舒服
I'm sick of watching you
sleep on your chair.
我们应该同床共枕
We're gonna share the bed.
我不觉得这是一个好主意
I dongt think it's a good idea.
不错
It's okay.
把你的腿放到床上
Put your legs up on the bed.
好，这样很好
Yeah. That's nice.
躺下，很好，放松
Put your head down.
It's okay. Relax.
晚安，利昂
Good night. Leon.
晚安
Good night.
我要第一块蛋糕！
I want a piece of cake first!
麦诺劳，带孩子们去厨房
Manolo. take the kids
in the kitchen.
我对你的生意很尊重，托尼
I have a lot of respect
for your business. Tony.
你以前为我们杀人的时候…
When you've killed for us
in the past...
我们总是很满意
we've always been satisfied.
那就是为什么对我来说今天很难过
That's exactly why today
is going to be very hard for me.
请恕我冒犯
I hope you'll excuse my mood.
我的手下在你的地盘死了
My man was killed
right here on your turf.
那些中国佬说那个杀手…
The Chinks tell me
that the hit man...
好像是意大利人
was kind of the Italian type.
所以我估计托尼能提供点儿消息
So we figured that Tony
might know something.
等等，还有
Wait. There's more.
你会喜欢听的
You're gonna love this.
几小时前，一个12岁大的小姑娘
来到我办公室…
A few hours later. a little 1 2-year-old
girl comes into my office...
武装到了牙齿
很执着的要送我去太平间
armed to the teeth. with the firm
intention of sending me to the morgue.
你知道谁来大厦带走了她吗？
Do you know who came and got her
right there in my building?
一样的…
The very same...
意大利杀手
Italian hit man.
我渴望见他一面
I'm dying to meet him.
放松，一切正常，睡的好吗？
Relax. Everything's fine.
Sleep well?
我从来没有真正睡着
总是睁一眼闭一眼
I never really sleep.
Got one eye open always.
是啊，我忘了
Yeah. I forgot.
我从没见过睁一眼闭一眼的人
打呼噜这么厉害
I never saw someone with one eye open
snore so much.
- 我打呼噜？
- 就跟一个婴儿一样
- I snore?
- Like a baby.
我要去买点早餐牛奶，马上就回来
I'm gonna get some milk for breakfast.
I wongt be long.
你回来的时候别忘了暗号
Dongt forget the code
when you come back.
两下，一下，再两下，是吧？
Two knocks. then one.
and two knocks again. Right?
对
Right.
先算这些，我去拿点牛奶
Ring these up.
I'm gonna go get some milk.
从现在开始，你不许出声
From here on out.
you dongt make a sound.
你回答我的问题，点头是摇头不是
你明白吗？
You answer my questions
by nodding yes or shaking your head no.
他一个人吗？
Is he alone?
他在等你回去吗？
Does he expect you?
你有房间钥匙吗？
Do you have keys
to the apartment?
有敲门的暗号吗，让他知道是你？
Is there a code. a way of knocking.
so he knows it's you?
第一组
Alpha team.
- 已经就位，我们准备行动
- 小心点
- Final position. We're ready to go.
- Be careful.
怎么了？闪开！操
What up? Move! Fuck.
靠
Shit.
第一组，有人牺牲
Alpha team. Man down.
我早跟你说过了
I told you.
班尼
- 把所有人都找来
- 你什么意思，“所有人”？
- Bring me everyone.
- What do you mean. ''everyone''?
所有人！
Everyone!
拿着
Take this.
过去看看
Go take a look.
- 不许动
- 你看到了什么？
- Dongt move.
- Do you see anything?
是那个家伙，他就在这儿
用枪指着我的头
It's the guy. He's here.
He's got a gun to my head.
大家别动
Nobody moves.
- 放了那女孩儿
- 别紧张，哥们！
- Let the girl go.
- Take it easy. man!
放了那女孩儿
好，那女孩儿过来了，放了那女孩儿
Okay. the girl's coming out.
Let the girl go.
把墙上的斧头拿下来，那儿，快！
Grab the axe off the wall.
Over there. Go!
你跟我们一起来
You're coming with us.
上帝啊，他向他开枪了！
Christ. he shot him!
混蛋！
Bastard!
退后！退后！退后！
Move!
- 关掉他妈的水阀！
- 明白
- Shut the fucking water off!.
- Got it.
来！
Come!
我们这儿有麻烦，派援兵来
重复，派援兵来
We're in a bad way here.
Send the cats.
我不知道出什么事了
我没看见他们来，我发誓！
I dongt know what happened.
I didngt see 'em coming. I swear!
我只是去购物然后就回来
然后他们就满地都是了
I just went shopping and I came back.
and they were everywhere.
离开窗户，玛蒂尔达
Stay away from the window.
过来
Come here.
狙击手
Snipers.
好，现在，干掉那个混蛋吧
Okay. now. get this fucking asshole
out of there.
- 我们现在怎么离开这儿？
- 这事交给我，我们试试
- How are we gonna get outta here now?
- Leave it to me. We're checking out.
这太小了你下不去啊，我才刚刚好
But it's not big enough for you.
It's barely big enough for me.
- 我们说过不能讨价还价的
- 不，我不能让…
- We said no discussion.
- No. I'm not letting--
- 我不走，我不会走的！
- 听我说
- I'm not going! I wongt go!
- Listen to me.
我们在一起一点机会都没有
但如果我是一个人，我能做得到
We have no chance together.
But if I'm alone. I can do it.
相信我吧，我有数
Trust me.
I'm in good shape.
我在托尼那儿有一大笔钱
I know I've got a lot
of money with Tony.
我们会取出来然后一起离开
就我们俩，好吗？
We'll take it and leave together.
just the two of us.
走吧
Go.
你这么说了我就不担心了
You're saying that
so I wongt worry.
- 我不能失去你
- 你不会失去我的
- I dongt wanna lose you.
- You're not gonna lose me.
你让我体会到了生命的美好
You've given me
a taste for life.
我想高高兴兴的安安稳稳的在床上睡觉
I wanna be happy.
sleep in a bed. have roots.
你不会再孤独了
You'll never be alone again.
求求你，现在就走，宝贝，走吧
Please. go now. baby. Go.
冷静点，现在就走，快走
Calm down.
Go now. Go.
托尼那儿见，我们把他们都解决掉
过一小时托尼那儿见
See you at Tony's. I'm gonna
clean them all. Tony's in an hour.
我爱你，玛蒂尔达
I love you. Mathilda.
我也爱你，利昂
I love you. too. Leon.
嘿，上面那儿出什么事了？
是抓那个人，不是抓这栋大楼
Hey. what is going on up there?
Take the guy out. not the building.
我们发现一个还活着的！
We've got one breathing here!
快叫医生来！
Get a medic on the horn!
闪开！让他过去！
Clear the hall!
Let him through!
- 我们有伤员，让开！
- 走楼梯下去
- We've got a wounded man. Make way!
- Down those stairs.
我们上！行动！
Let's go! Move!
带这家伙离开楼梯！
Get that guy off the stairs!
- 带你的组回去！
- 我送他！
- Get your team back out there!
- I got him!
我们有两个人下楼梯了，快点！
We've got two men coming
down the stairs. Let's hurry!
你没事吧？嘿，我这儿需要医生！
You okay?
Hey. I need a medic over here!
都给我动起来
Move your fucking asses.
第一小队，房间里什么情况？
Squad Number One.
what's the status on the apartment?
啥也看不见，烟太浓了，给我五分钟
Cangt see shit. Too much smoke.
Give us five minutes.
好吧
You got it.
什么？两百人都找不到
一个男人和一个小女孩儿？
What? Two hundred men cangt find
one man and a girl?
你找到那个小女孩儿了吗？
Did you find the girl?
你怎么样？摘下面罩，快点
How are you doing?
Take your mask off. quick.
让我看看，很深，好，这边…
Let me see you. That's deep.
Right. And this one here--
你是第三分局的吗？
You're from the 3rd Precinct?
让我们看看，他的袖子有点儿大
Let's open up
his sleeve a little bit.
好吧，没事，放下来，这条
All right. fine. Put it down.
This one.
你在这儿等两分钟，我马上回来
You stay there for two minutes.
I'll be right back.
让我带着面罩吧，能呼吸顺畅点
Let me put the mask back on.
I breathe better with it.
你说的对，坐好
You're all right.
Sit tight.
快点，所有人都出去！快走！出去！
Come on. everybody out!
Let's go! Out!
让路，哥们儿们
Clear the way. men.
你在这儿干什么？出去，快点
What are you doing here?
Get out. Come on.
斯丹斯菲尔德
为您效劳
At your service.
这是…
This is from...
玛蒂尔达送你的
Mathilda.
靠
Shit.
快离开这儿！
Get out of here!
利昂曾叫我照顾你…
Leon asked me
to help you out...
如果出事了，我想肯定是出事了
if something happened.
and I think something happened.
他给你留了点儿钱
He put aside
a little cash for you.
我的建议是…
So what I'm suggesting
is that...
你年纪这么小…
seeing as how
you're still so young...
我将替你保管这笔钱，直到你长大
I should hold the money for you
until you're older.
就像银行，你知道，只是…
Like a bank. you know. except...
比银行更好，因为银行总是会倒闭的
it's better than a bank
'cause banks always get knocked off.
老托尼这儿不会
No one knocks off old Tony.
但这是你的钱…
But it's your money.
In the meantime...
你需要做的就是每隔一段时间来一趟…
all you gotta do is come here
every once in awhile...
我会给你一些，让你有点零花钱
and I'll dish it out
so you can have a little fun.
给
Here.
- 这是开头的一百块钱
- 能给我个活儿干吗？
- Here's a hundred bucks to start.
- Cangt I get a job instead?
活儿？你到底能干什么？
Ajob?
What the hell can you do?
我可以杀人
I can clean.
我没有活儿给一个12岁的小孩儿…
I aingt got no work
for a 1 2-year-old kid...
所以别痴心妄想了！
so get it out
of your goddamn head!
结束了！游戏结束了！
It's over!
The game's over!
利昂已经死了！
Leongs dead!
你听见我说的了吗？
You hear me?
拜托，你觉得我不伤心吗？
Come on. You think
I aingt hurting too?
但他已经死了
But he's dead.
你要忘记这些发狂的事
给我回学校去
You're gonna forget all this craziness
and get your little ass back to school.
现在拿钱走人吧
Now take this money
and get the hell outta here.
不到下个月别过来…
Dongt let me see your face
till next month...
因为我有名的好脾气已经快耗尽了
'cause something tells me
I'm about to lose my famous kind streak.
“斯宾塞中学”
我的父母…
My parents...
死了…
died...
四周前的一场车祸
in a car accident
four weeks ago.
这太可怕了
It was terrible.
当你第一次来这儿的时候
我们没有时间去互相了解…
We didngt have the time to get to know
one another when you first came here...
但我要你知道我不是那种
会让孩子失望的女人…
but I want you to know I'm not the kind
of woman who'd let down a child...
无论她什么情况，无论她犯了什么错
whatever her situation.
whatever her mistake.
所以我将会尽力帮助你
欢迎回到这儿
So I'm going to help you and do my best
to welcome you here again.
但有一个前提条件
But on one condition:
你必须跟我说实话，玛蒂尔达
You have to stop lying to me.
Mathilda.
我希望你把握机会…
I want you to take a chance...
并且相信我
and trust me.
告诉我你到底发生什么事了
Tell me what happened to you.
我的家人被禁毒署的官员枪杀了…
My family got shot down
by D.E.A. officers...
是因为毒品的问题
because of a drug problem.
之后我跟一个全世界最好的人
生活在一起
I left with the greatest guy on Earth.
他是个杀手，这儿最棒的
但他今早死了
He was a hit man. the best in town.
but he died this morning.
如果你不帮我，我今晚就会死掉
If you dongt help me.
I'll be dead by tonight.
- 你认识她吗？
- 我从来没有见过她
- You know her?
- I've never seen her.
我想我们在这儿会过的很好的，利昂
I think we'll be okay here.
$ He deals the cards as a meditation
And those he plays never suspect
$ He doesn't play for the money he wins
He doesn't play for respect
$ He deals the cards to find the answer
The sacred geometry of chance
$ The hidden law of a probable outcome
The numbers lead a dance
$ I know that the spades
are the swords of a soldier
$ I know that the clubs
are weapons of war
$ I know that diamonds
mean money for this art
$ But that's not
the shape of my heart
$ He may play the jack of diamonds
He may lay the queen of spades
$ He may conceal a king in his hand
While the memory of it fades
$ I know that the spades
are the swords of a soldier
$ I know that the clubs
are weapons of war
$ I know that diamonds
mean money for this art
$ That's not
the shape of my heart
$ And if I told you
that I loved you
$ You'd maybe think
there's something wrong
$ I'm not a man of too many faces
The mask I wear is one
$ Those who speak know nothing
And find out to their cost
$ Like those who curse their luck
in too many places
$ And those who fear are lost
$ I know that the spades
are the swords of a soldier
$ I know that the clubs
are weapons of war
$ I know that diamonds
mean money for this art
$ But that's not
the shape of my heart
$ That's not